TRONG TU LUU

37 Poplar Place, SE28 8BA +447424248605 <u>luutu2410@gmail.com</u>

Personal Profile

Problem solving was one of the skills which I developed during 4 years of studying Computer Science (Programming). Computer Science has helped me develop concentration and creativity. When coding, I have to focus on my project; attention to detail is important as one mistake causes an error in the whole programme. I am able to detect and fix this. Therefore, I also learned more skills while I worked as waiter, where I can plan my time and work well under pressure, whilst remaining positive. Another motivation to pursue a career in software engineering is because the discipline is so vast and involves a wide range of responsibilities in both computer applications and systems. This allows me to work in the field or fields that most interest me. For example: Website, Game Developer, Applications, Artificial Intelligence. To be able to step over barriers in the future I want to learn from professionals and work as a professional.

Education

Sept 2021 – Present - City, University of London – BSc Computer Science Year

1 Modules

+ Mathematics - 1st

+ System Architecture - 1st

+ Databases - 2:1

+ Programming in Java - 2:1

Sept 2019 – July 2021 - Notre Dame Catholic Sixth Form College – A Levels

- A Level Mathematics Grade A
- A Level Further Mathematics Grade C
- A Level Computer Science Grade B

(Language C# via Visual Studio Code & Database via Microsoft SQL Server)

Oct 2017 - July 2019 - Carr Manor Community School - GCSE

- OCR Mathematics Grade 8
- Edexcel English Language Grade 4
- OCR Computer Science Grade 4 (Basic Python)
- Certificate in Creative iMedia Pass at lv2 (Design & Edit Website)

Languages

Vietnamese (Native)

English

Technical Skills (Willing to learn more languages, follow the trends to build up my knowledge)

Microsoft Office – AdvancedJava - IntermediateC# - IntermediatePython – Beginner

 ${\bf SQL-Intermediate} \qquad \qquad {\bf Photoshop-Intermediate}$

Transferable Skills

Communication - As a Waiter, I worked with customers regularly, helping them with any queries they had.

I ensured they left happy by always listening to them in order to solve their queries efficiently and effectively **Problem Solving** – When I have difficulties, I determine the source of a problem and find an effective solution by researching, analysing, communicating.

Work Experience

Dec 2019 - Oct 2020 - Viet Guys Restaurant (Waiter) -

Taking customer's orders.

- Taking bookings through telephone.
- Delivering foods and drinks to customer's table and working as a bartender to serve basic drink and beverages.
- Making menu recommendations, answering questions, and sharing additional information with restaurant patrons.
- Up-sell additional products when appropriate.
- Deliver checks and collect bill payments.
- Greet and escort customers to their tables.
- Cleaning the dining area and toilet after closing time.

March 2019 - Oct 2019 - Fairy Nails Bradford (Receptionist) -

Taking bookings through telephone and social media.

- Arranging booking time slot of guests.
- Welcoming guests and directing guests to suitable seats.
- Completing the payment process from customers.
- Making tea or coffee for customers.
- Cleaning the floor and reception's desk.

Projects

- Gym System (C++ & SQL)

This project is to give directions and examples for one or more forms of exercise, physical activity, dietary regimens, or other fitness topics to the user. It also links to database for users save their daily routine, so they could know what to eat, what exercise should they do, the app also let user calculate your body fat and tell you what level user is.

- Snake Game (Java)

On first 2 weeks, my university give me a chance to learn and get familiar to Java. This processing project demonstrates a comprehensive understanding of the use of PVector, Array List, Classes. After all challenges in this project, I could make it work as same as original version.

- Functional Database (SQL)

In this project I have developed my ability to communicate in a business context and worked on a creative task. This project provided me with the technical knowledge and the skills such as: design relational databases, implement databases using a Relational Database Management System, use SQL to interrogate relational databases, specify SQL queries to solve data retrieval problems, model and design a database to meet a given requirements specification, use IT effectively

Interests

In my spare time, I would like to play sports like badminton and football to keep myself active and healthy. When I get home, I normally watched YouTube about games, coding competition, some programming projects,...There was one project that get in to my head, about neural network, people train AI to play games, sounds amazing to me to be honest.

References

Are available upon request